Carolina Power and Light Photograph Collection PHC.68
State Archives of North Carolina
- Marketing-Modern and Old School Lighting Display. A display is seen of modern and old school rooms. The old school room is seen dimly lit next to the brighter modern school room. Interior of the modern school room is shown up close with writing on the blackboard and a teacher seated at the desk. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.426.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Various Retail Interiors. Various interior views are seen all lit with electric light. The S&W Cafeteria in Asheville, NC is seen, Taylor's Department Store, Dr. Neal's waiting room, an unidentified banquet hall, and an unidentified department store are all seen. c. 1930s-40s, PhC.68.1.427.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Lighting Display c. 1950s. Pictured is a small display set up to demonstrate lighting techniques for various applications. A small living room scene is pictured with a desk, table, chair, and floor lamp. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.428; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Tide Water Power Company Parade Float c. 1930. Pictured is a parade float decorated for the 50th anniversary of electric lighting by Tide Water Power Company. The float depicts a power station and is seen at a rail yard. c. 1930, PhC.68.1.429; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Carolina Power and Light Parade Float on Hillsborough Street in Raleigh, NC c. 1950s. Pictured is a Carolina Power and Light Christmas parade float seen on the 900 block of Hillsborough Street in Raleigh, NC. Women are seen on the float waving to crowd. 907 Hillsborough Street (Joel Whitaker House) can be seen in the background. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.430; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Azalea Festival, Wilmington, NC c. 1955. Three scenes from the Azalea Festival in Wilmington, NC. The Lions Club Parade float is seen with women riding, Coble Dairy Products float is seen, and a Carolina Power and Light float is seen. c. 1955, PhC.68.1.431.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Azalea Festival, Wilmington, NC c. 1970s. Four color 8x10 photographs depicting three different years of Carolina Power and Light parade floats at the annual Azalea Festival in Wilmington, NC c. 1970s. All floats are made in the image of a ship but are slightly different. c. 1970s, PhC.68.1.432.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Azalea Festival, Wilmington, NC c. 1970s. Two 8x10 color photographs of a Carolina Power and Light parade float at the Wilmington, NC Azalea Festival. A horse and carriage with people riding is seen on top of the float c. 1970s, PhC.68.1.433.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Azalea Festival, Wilmington, NC c. 1970s. Four 8x10 color photographs of a Carolina Power and Light parade float at the Wilmington, NC Azalea Festival. The pink, decorated float has women standing and waving to the crowds c. 1970s, PhC.68.1.434.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Azalea Festival, Wilmington, NC c. 1970s. Three color and one black and white 8x10 prints depicting the Wilmington, NC Azalea Festival. The Carolina Power and Light Parade Float is pictured. A spaceship with an alien and a woman are seen on the float, waving to the crowds. c. 1970s, PhC.68.1.435.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Azalea Festival, Wilmington, NC c. 1970s. Pictured is a Carolina Power and Light parade float traveling down 3rd Street in Wilmington, NC during the Azalea Festival. The float depicts the Mother Goose nursery rhyme, "The Old Woman Who Lived in a Shoe". Woman and children are seen on the float waving to the crowds lining the street. A Belk store and a Gulf gas station are seen in the background of one picture. The New Hanover county courthouse is seen in the background of the other picture. c. 1970s, PhC.68.1.436.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Refrigerator in Modern Kitchen c. 1931. A kitchen scene is pictured with a woman placing something inside a refrigerator. c. 1931, PhC.68.1.437; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Ad For Refrigerator in Modern Kitchen c. 1950s, Late 1930s., PhC.68.1.438.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Energy Education, Model by Willie Biggs, September 1952. Pictured is a model completed by Willie Biggs depicting a scene with a power station with overhead lines running from it and other small structures including a gas station. A tractor and small cars can also be seen. September 1952, PhC.68.1.439; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Woman and Stove c. 1930s. Pictured is a woman in a dress and apron posing next to an electric range dating to 1913. The door to the oven is open. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.440; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-1914 Westinghouse Type 319 Electric Range/Oven. Pictured is a 1914 Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Co. Type 319 electric range/oven. This model was advertised in L. V. Sutton's 1914 Electric Cookbook. c. 1914, PhC.68.1.441; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Universal Electric Range c. 1930s. Pictured is a Universal electric range. A coffee pot and a clock are seen on top of the range. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.442; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Stoves. Two photographs used for marketing of electric stoves. A woman wearing an apron is seen in a kitchen adjusting a Westinghouse stove. Also seen is an advertising display featuring a cut out of a woman cooking in a kitchen beside an electric stove and other electric appliances on a table beside the stove. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.443; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Woman With Electric Toaster. A woman is seen seated at a dining table with breakfast while taking a piece of toast out of an electric toaster. c. 1924, PhC.68.1.444; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-1924 Vacuum Cleaner. A female housekeeper is seen in a living area next to a piano vacuuming a rug. c. 1924, PhC.68.1.445; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Vacuum Cleaner Demonstration at Raleigh, NC Carolina Power and Light Office c. 1925. A man is seen demonstrating a Hoover Vacuum cleaner outside the Raleigh, NC Carolina Power and Light Office on the corner of Hargett and Fayetteville Streets. c. 1925, PhC.68.1.446; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Vacuum Cleaner. A wall mounted vacuum cleaner is pictured with a hose attached. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.447; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Hoover Vacuum Cleaner Display c. 1925. A Hoover vacuum cleaner sales display is seen. A model living room is seen with lamp table and chair with a cardboard cutout of a girl vacuuming a carpet. c. 1925, PhC.68.1.448; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Hoover Vacuum Cleaner Christmas Display. A Christmas shopping display advertisement is seen with a vacuum and three wreaths next to the vacuum. "Give her a Hoover" is seen spelled out in garland. c. 1925, PhC.68.1.449; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Woman Washing Clothes. A woman is seen manually washing clothes in a bucket with a washboard on top of a chair. c. 1920s, PhC.68.1.450; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Washing Machine c. 1924. Pictured is a Minier Manufacturing Co. 2 in 1 washing machine c. 1924, PhC.68.1.451; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Electric Washing Machine Demonstration at Carolina Power and Light Office c. 1925. Eleven men (left to right, Andy Scroggs, H. G. Isley, L. L. Betts, Pug Holbrook, Johnny McLean, Smokey Smith, Ray Veal, Ben Terrell, Beau Lumsden, Whitley DeeBose, Lehman Wood) are seen at the entrance to the offices of Carolina Power and Light in the Raleigh Building on the corner of Fayetteville and Hargett Streets in Raleigh, NC. They are seen posing with a washing machine sales display. Washing machines are seen along with promotional material and a clothes line hung over the door with clothes on i, PhC.68.1.452; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Washing Machines. Two product pictures for advertising purposes of Westinghouse washing machines. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.453.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Signs, Electric c. 1940s. Advertising window display featuring a lighted sign advertising Lumiline Signs. The advertisement reads, "Merchants Boost Your Sales, Use Lumiline Signs". c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.454; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Woman at Washing Machine. A woman is seen in a kitchen placing clothing into a washing machine. A dryer is seen next to the washing machine. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.455; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-War Bonds Advertisement. Window advertisement for war bonds and stamps and promoting health. Signs read, "Vitamins for Victory" and "Join the Health for Victory Club". A cut out of Uncle Sam is seen standing next to display. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.456; Carolina Power and Light
- Mt. Gilead, NC Fire, January 1959. A building on a city street in Mt. Gilead, NC is seen with flames bursting from windows and doors. A power pole on the street has started to ignite. January 1959, PhC.68.1.457; Carolina Power and Light
- Myrtle Beach, SC, Storms, Fire on Ocean Drive c. 1950s. A utility pole with electric lines and several transformer is seen at night with sparks flying from it, Ocean Drive, SC c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.458; Carolina Power and Light
- Southern Pines, Office Fire, 4 September 1969. Scenes from a fire at a Southern Pines office. A burnt filing cabinet is seen, an overall view of the damaged office, and a woman is seen sorting through burnt file cabinet drawers inside an office. 4 September 1969, PhC.68.1.459.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Asheville, NC, Flood of 1916, French Broad River, PhC.68.1.460.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
  - Riverside Park from south end after Asheville flood of 16 July 1916. Debris is seen piled against bank of French Broad River. Original panoramic photograph consisting of two physically attached photographs. Overall print measures 7.5"x21". July 1916, PhC.68.1.460.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - The French Broad river is seen one day after the Flood of 1916. Left side of photograph shows Asheville Power and Light Plant and gas house surrounded by receding flood waters. Water line can be seen approximately 6 feet above water level seen., PhC.68.1.460.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - Elevated view of the French Broad River showing a flooded industrial district after the flood of 16 July 1916. Asheville Power and Light and Gas House are seen in distance along with concrete bridge crossing the French Broad River at present day (July 2015) location of Haywood Road bridge. People are seen lining the bridge and surrounding area. Debris is seen backed up against bridge pilings. 16 July 1916, PhC.68.1.460.3; Carolina Power and Light
- Asheville, NC, Flood of 1928, French Broad River., PhC.68.1.461.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
  - Elevated view of a flooded French Broad River district in Asheville, NC. Various sites are labeled on photograph. They include, Gas Plant and Avery Street Substation, Southern Railway Passenger Depot, Southern Railway Freight Depot, Battery Park Hotel, George Vanderbilt Hotel, Carolina Power and Light Car Barn, Pack Square, Jackson Building, and the Langren Hotel. August 1928, PhC.68.1.461.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - The Avery Street Substation (approximate present day (July 2015) location of Riverside Drive near the Haywood Road bridge) is seen flooded. Three African American men are seen pushing a cart through the deep flood waters with a white man riding. Warehouses and rail cars can be seen in the background., PhC.68.1.461.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - View of Gas Plant and Avery Street Substation in Asheville, NC after 1928 Flooding., PhC.68.1.461.3; Carolina Power and Light
- Lumberton, NC, Flood c.1940s. Aerial photograph of a flooded electrical substation in Lumberton, NC. Estimated c.1940, PhC.68.1.462; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Connie, Jacksonville, NC, 12 August 1955., PhC.68.1.463.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
  - An interior wall is seen with a cord plugged into an electrical outlet. There is a line on the wall approximately 2 feet above the floor created by flood waters., PhC.68.1.463.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - Hurricane Connie, Jacksonville, NC, 12 August 1955. A man is seen standing in front of a desk measuring its height with a ruler. The desk is sitting on four electric meters., PhC.68.1.463.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - Hurricane Connie, Jacksonville, NC, 12 August 1955. Line workers are seen outdoors in the rain working to repair damaged caused by Hurricane Connie., PhC.68.1.463.3; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Diane, Morehead City, NC, August 1955., PhC.68.1.464.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - Storm damage from hurricane Connie is seen. Two ocean front buildings are seen next to leaning power poles and debris., PhC.68.1.464.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - Storm damage from hurricane Connie is seen. Residential area is seen experiencing high winds and power poles are seen leaning., PhC.68.1.464.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - Storm debris is seen on the beach next to a pier. Back of photograph is captioned, "Weeks and Andrews contractor crew replace pole at Atlantic City Fishing pier. Debris is part of bulkhead and cottage steps washed out by high tide and seas, carrying pole with it.", PhC.68.1.464.3; Carolina Power and Light
  - Men are seen on a residential street collecting fallen limbs in the back of a dump truck., PhC.68.1.464.4; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Donna, September 1960., PhC.68.1.465.1-7; Carolina Power and Light
  - Carolina Power and Light work trucks are seen along the side of a rural road while linemen repair damaged power lines., PhC.68.1.465.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - A crane is seen being used to clean storm damage. Railroad tracks are seen beside a roadway with a boat strewn over both., PhC.68.1.465.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - A Carolina Power and Light utility truck is seen with two workers repairing electrical lines. One worker is seen on the ground, one is on top of a power pole., PhC.68.1.465.3; Carolina Power and Light
  - A work truck is seen holding up a power pole as a utility worker works on the top of the pole. Traffic and parked cars can also be seen along the roadway., PhC.68.1.465.4; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two utility workers are seen in a residential area. One is seen on top of a power pole, one is seen on the ground. A large house is seen in the background., PhC.68.1.465.5; Carolina Power and Light
  - A boat is seen sitting in the middle of a roadway as workers are seen attempting to attach a cable connected to a crane., PhC.68.1.465.6; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Donna, 11-12 September 1960., PhC.68.1.466.1-16; Carolina Power and Light
  - A destroyed residence is seen at Atlantic Beach, NC. Debris is strewn about as two people are seen sitting on a wall., PhC.68.1.466.01; Carolina Power and Light
  - Boats are seen piled up on the shore of a sound., PhC.68.1.466.02; Carolina Power and Light
  - A boat is seen in Swansboro, NC sitting on the side of a street. Local businesses can be seen in background., PhC.68.1.466.03; Carolina Power and Light
  - Appears to be a drive-in movie theater sign that has been blown down during Hurricane Donna. The theater's sign is seen on left., PhC.68.1.466.04; Carolina Power and Light
  - The foundation of a house is seen with no walls. All that remains is bedroom furniture. The walls of the house can be seen on ground., PhC.68.1.466.05; Carolina Power and Light
  - A Rambler Motor Co. dealership is seen. The sign for the business is seen bent over almost touching the ground. No other damage seen., PhC.68.1.466.06; Carolina Power and Light
  - The roof of the Dunes Club at Atlantic Beach is seen in foreground. Back is captioned, "Dunes Club-damage- Oceana in background., PhC.68.1.466.07; Carolina Power and Light
  - Boats are seen piled up on land in Swansboro, NC as a result of Hurricane Donna., PhC.68.1.466.08; Carolina Power and Light
  - Wreckage is seen at Causeway in Swansboro, NC as boats are seen on top of railroad tracks. People are seen walking around inspecting damage., PhC.68.1.466.09; Carolina Power and Light
  - A train engine is seen on left side of badly damaged railroad tracks. A boat is seen on right side of tracks along with other debris, PhC.68.1.466.10; Carolina Power and Light
  - A power pole is seen broken at base, severely leaning., PhC.68.1.466.11; Carolina Power and Light
  - Power poles are seen toppled over along major highway., PhC.68.1.466.12; Carolina Power and Light
  - A train engine is seen on right side of frame partially sunken into ground. Surrounded by debris., PhC.68.1.466.13; Carolina Power and Light
  - A waterway is seen with a concrete bridge crossing it. Power poles are seen in waterway with some broken and leaning. A man stands looking out over water., PhC.68.1.466.14; Carolina Power and Light
  - A power pole is seen leaning along a highway., PhC.68.1.466.15; Carolina Power and Light
  - A house and car are seen with debris and wreckage including several boats. A damaged and leaning barn is seen in background. Swansboro, NC, PhC.68.1.466.16; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Donna, 11-12 September 1960., PhC.68.1.467.1-17; Carolina Power and Light
  - Carolina Power and Light workers are seen freeing a power line from a tree with a long tool., PhC.68.1.467.01; Carolina Power and Light
  - Carolina Power and Light workers are seen installing a new power pole after one was broken in half. The broken pole is seen next to the new one., PhC.68.1.467.02; Carolina Power and Light
  - A pine tree is seen leaning up on power lines., PhC.68.1.467.03; Carolina Power and Light
  - Carolina Power and Light workers are seen on power poles repairing damage near Meadow Seafood Company., PhC.68.1.467.04; Carolina Power and Light
  - A work truck is seen holding up a power pole as a utility worker works on the top of the pole. Traffic and parked cars can also be seen along the roadway., PhC.68.1.467.05; Carolina Power and Light
  - A power pole is seen broken in half and leaning over the Vacation office in Morehead City, PhC.68.1.467.06; Carolina Power and Light
  - Power poles are seen leaning near a major highway, PhC.68.1.467.07; Carolina Power and Light
  - Three Carolina Power and Light workers are seen looking at large metal box containing electrical infrastructure inside., PhC.68.1.467.08; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two soldiers are seen talking with a man in a car on a main street in Beaufort, NC., PhC.68.1.467.09; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two Carolina Power and Light line workers are seen at the top of a power pole performing repairs. A railroad crossing signal can be seen in foreground., PhC.68.1.467.10; Carolina Power and Light
  - Power poles are seen toppled over an leaning along a major road, PhC.68.1.467.11; Carolina Power and Light
  - Three Carolina Power and Light workers are seen in an office. One is seen preparing to speak into a microphone., PhC.68.1.467.12; Carolina Power and Light
  - Contact Sheet containing frames from previous files associated with Hurricane Donna, PhC.68.1.467.13-17; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Donna, 11-12 September 1960., PhC.68.1.468.1-12; Carolina Power and Light
  - The Morehead-Beaufort causeway is pictured. A cracked and flooded roadway is seen amongst wreckage including railroad tracks, a train engine, boats and debris., PhC.68.1.468.01; Carolina Power and Light
  - Debris is seen near a sound area at Atlantic Beach/Ft. Macon vicinity, PhC.68.1.468.02; Carolina Power and Light
  - A beach-front residence is seen with a collapsed front porch roof at Atlantic Beach, PhC.68.1.468.03; Carolina Power and Light
  - A boy is seen standing on a large branch of a pine tree that has fallen on a house behind him. Jacksonville, NC, PhC.68.1.468.04; Carolina Power and Light
  - A boat is seen in Swansboro, NC sitting on the side of a street. Local businesses can be seen in background, PhC.68.1.468.05; Carolina Power and Light
  - A Rambler Motor Co. dealership is seen. The sign for the business is seen bent over almost touching the ground. No other damage seen., PhC.68.1.468.06; Carolina Power and Light
  - A small boy is seen standing in the shattered front window of an Esso service station looking directly at camera. A woman is seen sitting at a desk inside while another woman is seen standing behind it, talking on the phone., PhC.68.1.468.07; Carolina Power and Light
  - A house is seen destroyed in Atlantic Beach, NC., PhC.68.1.468.08; Carolina Power and Light
  - A house and car are seen with debris and wreckage including several boats. A damaged and leaning barn is seen in background. Swansboro, NC, PhC.68.1.468.09; Carolina Power and Light
  - A house and car are seen with debris and wreckage including several boats., PhC.68.1.468.10; Carolina Power and Light
  - The roof of the Dunes Club at Atlantic Beach is seen in foreground. Back is captioned, "Dunes Club, Atlantic Beach"., PhC.68.1.468.11; Carolina Power and Light
  - A power pole in Morehead, NC is seen broken approximately 5 feet from the base and has fallen on local business, Atlas Tires., PhC.68.1.468.12; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Ginger, September 1971. A man and a woman are seen seated at a desk. The woman is wearing a rain hat, talking on the phone., PhC.68.1.469.1-9; Carolina Power and Light
  - Hurricane Ginger, September 1971. A man and a woman are seen seated at a desk. The woman is wearing a rain hat, talking on the phone., PhC.68.1.469.01; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two Carolina Power and Light workers are seen working to restore electrical service as man on right holds a wire while man on left cuts with large wire cutters. One man is identified as L. Quinton Williams, PhC.68.1.469.02; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two Carolina Power and Light workers are seen outdoors wearing hardhats. Left, Jack Cooper and right, L. Quinton Williams, PhC.68.1.469.03; Carolina Power and Light
  - Royland Boyd is seen in an office talking on the phone., PhC.68.1.469.04; Carolina Power and Light
  - Earl Thorpe is seen standing in an office motioning to someone., PhC.68.1.469.05; Carolina Power and Light
  - Carolina Power and Light trucks are seen along a street repairing damage caused by Hurricane Ginger. Possibly Raleigh, NC., PhC.68.1.469.06; Carolina Power and Light
  - Carolina Power and Light trucks are seen along a street repairing damage caused by Hurricane Ginger. Possibly Raleigh, NC., PhC.68.1.469.07; Carolina Power and Light
  - A Carolina Power and Light worker is seen at the top of a power pole repairing damage caused by Hurricane Ginger., PhC.68.1.469.08; Carolina Power and Light
  - 12 Contact prints of previous files., PhC.68.1.469.09; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Hazel, 15 October 1954. Various scenes of Swansboro, NC and Morehead City after Hurricane Hazel in October of 1954. The streets of Swansboro are flooded with debris and wreckage. The Swansboro Fishing Pier is seen in floodwaters, breaking apart. Boats are seen washed ashore on streets and yards. The Water Front Restaurant is seen flooded and surrounded by waters from the sound. A dog is seen on the front step of a residence surrounded by floodwaters., PhC.68.1.470.1-20; Carolina Power and Light
- Hurricane Hazel, 15 October 1954., PhC.68.1.471.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
  - Unidentified beach, destroyed structures and debris is seen after Hurricane Hazel, PhC.68.1.471.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - Scene looking south down Atlantic Beach. Large ocean front building is seen destroyed in foreground., PhC.68.1.471.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - Photo is captioned, "The signal tower at Southport, NC Showing hurricane flags torn to shreds and the metal most permanently bent after the fury of Hurricane Hazel on October 15, 1954"., PhC.68.1.471.3; Carolina Power and Light
  - Portion of Southport, NC. Buildings are seen destroyed, debris is scattered over landscape. Three men are seen in distance surveying damage., PhC.68.1.471.4; Carolina Power and Light